so we're going to start with this uh
image number
5.34 and uh this guy represents medicine
Buddha and today we're gonna talk about
the question of how do you ask them for
help okay how do you ask the medicine
buddas for help when you need help how
do you ask them for help and then what
is it about medicine Buddha that can
help you what can really help you okay
uh I think otherwise it just feels to me
like Superstition you know you if you
can go to a
statue and ask them for help then you
don't need classes you just ask the
statue for help you don't need gisha
then I can sleep you can sleep you know
we don't have to get up so early okay so
there must
be some kind of uh special method or
something we have to think about when we
ask medicine BR for help okay otherwise
we could just talk to the
Statue and but I I think we all
know uh it doesn't work to just go to a
temple and ask a statue for help uh we
we we wish that it helped and I I also
feel special when I go into the
temple uh and I lived in a temple for 25
years
uh you know you feel like you can almost
talked to the statues but it it doesn't
quite work that way and we need to
understand something about medicine
Buddha when we ask them for help okay so
we're going to start on that
today and we're taking the method uh you
know recommended by Aya nagaj who lived
about 2,000 years ago and he's the
greatest emptiness teacher in
history uh so here we go how do you ask
a medicine Buddha for help uh and how do
you how does it work okay uh here's the
actual prayers in the next
section uh we ask that you extend your
holy Deeds pure and white to every
corner of this
universe uh we ask that you help each of
the members of our spiritual Community
succeed in all their attempts to
practice the 10 Good Deeds we ask that
you assist us to take this practice
every ever higher and ever
further
$100 s we do $100 bet in the morning to
wake up the
kids $100
bet what's the most important words here
for getting medicine Buddha to
work who's is that who's the I guess the
Box lady
decides ask which one ask uh no no
everybody ask nobody some people don't
get
answered not jig me she supposed to give
the
money it's okay it's okay jig
me not you
teachers Lindsay yeah
box hit Rob with the
box is it that it's for everyone like
each of the members assist us help
others yeah about
everybody say again is it that it's
about everybody like help each of the
members we ask that you assist us like
it's not just about uh no no what makes
the request
work the 10 good tis yeah
$100 uh we bought a car recently Rob
helped me for a month or six weeks he
bought two cars this recently we bought
one car for the Ukrainian ladies and and
then he bought another car from my uh
sister-in-law me and my wife sponsored a
car for my sister-in-law and so you know
why we sent Rob is he's good at reading
the small letters in the
contract and and we actually cancelled
like three cars because the small
letters said if it breaks you good luck
go away don't bother us you know and uh
so the small letter in this contract is
uh we ask you to help us and from our
side uh we will do the 10 Good Deeds
okay uh so you have to do something you
have to know what to do if you ask uh
even medicine Buddha for help uh you
better have some energy you better have
some Karma you better have some good
seeds so it's kind of a contract this
request is kind of like a contract you
know please help my relatives to stay
healthy please pleas help my family to
stay healthy please help all the people
but and from my side I I will keep the
10 good deals okay $100 for the 10 Good
Deeds no I mean who's going to give me
the 10 $10 each
de but by the way I'm not giving 70 or
60 I want the whole 100 okay do it slow
that's okay it's like number one I'll
say it from the positives not the
negatives I like that okay I prefer it
that's how you taught it we didn't say
help it doesn't say help us in our
attempts not to avoid the 10 bad it says
help us in our attempts to practice the
D
goodies okay uh three of body okay
protect life number one yay that's
$10 ding ding ding d d okay uh number
two honor others property
okay number three maintain sexual Purity
yeah and honor other people's
relationships yeah yeah and then moving
into speech good yeah uh speak
truthfully yeah always tell the truth uh
speak
meaningfully
uh not really speak
gently
oh speak in ways they bring other people
together
yeah okay do I give
$5 okay okay third one speak
gently speak gently yeah no bad words
don't don't use harsh words stupid idiot
or all the things Rime used to call
me they know okay uh speak pleas speak
gently speak in ways that put other peop
together help me out we we we don't I'll
lose the 10 for this help me out speak
meaningfully yeah don't blah blah Don't
gossip so is that four don't waste your
breath yeah we finish speech slowly we
finish speech okay sorry I'm on the spot
kind of early I uh three for mind yeah
uh when you see someone receive
something they like Rejoice yeah don't
be jealous don't be upset when someone
gets something they want then celebrate
by the way it doesn't come out of you
right it comes out of their seeds it
doesn't come don't the world is not a
pizza the world is not eight slices it's
not a zero some game you know the more
you rejoice the more slices there are
okay second when you see someone receive
something they don't like have empathy
yeah don't be happy when people get hurt
even if they're your enemies okay and
third one maintain a worldview of Karma
and emptiness yeah
[Applause]
just it's like pulling teeth from a
crow
they don't have tee
understand okay old old expression all
right
um next picture you guys I think it's
number
36 yeah yeah I like this one uh there's
a big question in the medicine Buddha by
the way we are
covering uh a medicine
Buddha prayer sadna 300 pages written by
the great fifth D okay and it's the
first time it's been translated John
Brady found the text okay
and and we we are translating 100 pages
each year uh so next year we'll finish
next year okay we we have 200 Pages done
and in this part they say something
strange they say uh when you ask the
Buddhist medicine Buddha for help try to
see that they are
they are total peace try to see the
medicine Buddha is total peace okay
that's what this guy is he's in total
peace okay he's also lazy no I'm just
kidding so you're supposed to see by the
way you're not supposed to
see that medicine Buddha is peaceful
you're supposed to see that they are
peace okay that's a big difference all
right it's not that they are happy and
smile smiling
this you know the story of the Statue is
kind of nice U my wife and I went to
dinner at a TOA [__] in
Sedona and um there was a huge
rainstorm just before we reached the
restaurant we went to
Renee and uh we had to duck into a a
shop and it was one of those cheap
Vortex crystal shops in Sedona they
charge you like $110 for a 10 cent
Crystal and we were like waiting for the
rain to finish and and the statue was
way way up on a shelf all dusty and and
I said is that statue are you selling
that statue and they said well it's just
up there you know and I said well can I
see it and we got a ladder and we got
the statue and uh it's it is medicine
Buddha medicine Buddha is called lais
lailai right that's one of the medicine
Buddhist names and that's a big piece of
L lapis lazuli under the under the metal
there's a boulder of lapis Lai if you
pick it up it's very heavy and there's a
you can see the Stone from underneath
there's only one place to get lapis is
uh Afghanistan and it's very difficult
to to go there it's very very dangerous
and very diff difficult to go there
somebody went there and found a a
serious piece of lapis which is very
rare and then they uh built the Statue
around the lapis and then they carved
the face and it's very beautiful so we
offered it to Dr
Woo me and my wife and our friends we
bought
it and took a lot of friends and we
offered it to Dr W and I'd like to thank
Dr wuo for his classes this week and
teaching those class
and also for helping us so much with the
stus okay uh so we're supposed to see
medicine Buddha as total peace all right
let's go to
ngar poetry and see what it means to see
medicine Buddha total
peace this is called three spheres okay
uh you can see it in the L RM uh you can
see it over almost 2,000 years later
you can see the the teaching of the
three spheres and it means uh when
there's an
action when when a medicine Buddha
doctor do you know Al this a doctor
anyway and an iron woman uh I saw you
running yesterday it's unbelievable it
it almost gave me a heart
attack just to watch her running up and
down the mountains you know uh but she's
also a mother and she's also a medical
doctor MD so
anyway uh when the doctor's helping you
it says here three three things are
going on okay and there's a holding by
something something holding and a holder
and something held he gives four four
but it comes down to three okay
sometimes they say three spheres
sometimes they say four spheres okay
there's a doctor okay the doctor is one
of the elements in an act of healing in
when you want to have an act of healing
when you want the doctor to help you uh
the first thing is the doctor okay uh
second thing
is the patient okay you can't have a
doctor without a patient right all right
so uh in the in the act of healing or
the act of helping people medically
there should be a doctor there should be
a patient then there should be a
huh you should say you could say the
active healing has to go on sometimes
you can add the medicine okay sometimes
you can add the medicine what does the
doctor give so there has to be basically
three things going on there has to be a
doctor there has to be a sick person and
something has to pass between them uh
which could be the action of of
treatment or the medicine which passes
between them so we call it the three
spheres okay
uh and here he says all three are total
peace and so there is no holding okay
all three are total peace and so there
is no holding okay the the
doctor the patient with with doctors
medicine Buddha patient which is us and
then healing us or our family members or
like that is the action and he says all
three are total peace okay all three are
total
peace $100 if you can tell me what total
peace means here do I have
enough okay what's total peace
here okay loud guess I try total peace
means um it's totally emptiness is not
things that which is not coming from our
side good perfect uh that's said $300
answer cuz three spheres
right I hope I hope we have that me you
can just give her I
you yeah good answer yeah we say they
are uh peaceful peace doesn't mean
they're nice and they don't get upset or
something like that it doesn't mean that
okay when we say they are at peace
what's the Sanskrit here aah Shanti okay
Shanti okay when we say the medicine
Buddha is at peace uh it means empty
emptiness okay at peace here means
emptiness emptiness is also how you get
to peace which is nirvana okay so the
peace here is emptiness okay what does
it mean the doctor's empty the medicine
Buddhist empty and joy said uh they're
coming from your seeds
okay who who gave birth to Medicine ver
his
mom you did okay you created the
medicine bu okay it and it by the way it
doesn't mean you can just close your
eyes or paint a medicine Buddha and then
ask it to cure your cancer or something
like that it doesn't work like that they
are creation of your seeds okay it
doesn't mean they are fake it doesn't
mean they are artificial it doesn't mean
you can paint them or make a sculpture
from an expensive piece of lapis and and
then that's medicine bu it doesn't mean
that okay it means uh your karmic seeds
from keeping
the okay from keeping the 10 Good Deeds
uh you created medicine Buddha okay and
that's part of the three spheres okay
and that's why medicine Buddha is at
peace okay peace in this case means
emptiness so is peace dependent
origination okay so I'll say it again if
they're coming from your seeds if
medicine Buddha who you ask for help is
coming from your seeds that's not
emptiness that's dependent origination
okay that's what they call
dependence is there emptiness there
don't
answer it's going to come later okay all
right it's going to come later but they
are he is that peace medicine Buddha is
at peace also the the doctors at peace
and Pati the patients at peace so the
the patients also coming from seeds the
patient also coming from seeds and the
illness of the patient is coming from
their own seats okay the illness of the
patient is coming from their own seats
the what makes a medicine Buddha doctor
so
effective is that they see your seeds
and they know how how to treat you they
see how your they don't look at your
blood pressure or your what do you call
it sugar levels they look at your karmic
seed levels okay probably there's a cuff
you put on your thing and you know they
check your caric seed levels okay and
and that's how they treat you and as I
said before I think one of the most
beautiful things to to think about when
you're asking medicine Buddha for help
Angelo you asked me a question two days
ago here's the answer all right it
usually comes in the class okay when you
ask medicine Buddha for
help uh you have to understand that they
see they are prescribing a medicine for
you because at the moment that they
prescribe it they see how it's going to
work two weeks from now okay so this a
weird kind of doctor okay okay they most
doctors they they give you a medicine
and they go home and tell their wife you
know I hope it works you and uh medicine
Buddha just picks out a medicine and
goes and they look into the future two
weeks from now three weeks from now they
say n this one won't work and then they
they choose another one and they oh yeah
take this one you're going to get better
in in 13 days and four hours you know
they can see wouldn't it be
nice to have a doctor who could see the
results Angelo your answer's in there
somewhere okay uh if you if you keep the
10 Good Deeds with enough effort and and
keep working on them every day uh and by
the way I there's two practices here one
is
confession one is
celebration
confession and celebration guess which
one I
prefer I mean I got lots of things to
confess I don't like confession I don't
know I just makes me feel negative you
know uh I'd rather focus on celebrating
the good things i' I've done okay and by
the way today we have uh in the evening
we have a
wedding and then we have rock and
roll because we have a visitor who will
be here who's a rock and roll star who's
agreed to play for us and then we'll do
a fire offering okay so bring your
dancing shoes
[Laughter]
again
okay uh so the Buddhist medicine
Buddhist at peace because the medicine
Buddha is coming from your and the
medicine Buddha patient
is you you also com in from your own
seats okay and then third one the
treatment the success of the treatment
whether the treatment's going to work or
not is also coming from your seed okay
so the doctor's coming from your seeds
the sickness was coming from your seeds
and the Cure is coming from your seeds
Okay so maybe you should make some good
seeds all right that's the thing okay
then they say at peace okay at peace it
means The Emptiness of the medicine The
Emptiness of the doctor The Emptiness of
the patient they're all at peace
okay why peace uh it means a stopping
peace here means a stopping okay the
stopping of
self-existence okay there's nothing
about the medicine
Buddha which is coming from the medicine
Buddha okay it's all coming from you
okay well guess then I'll just be a nice
person and forget forget them who needs
the
medicine doesn't work like that either
uh you need a you need to create a
medicine Buddha who takes care of you
okay it doesn't it doesn't work like
like that all
right then there's a last line
here uh there is no holding in the
Tibetan it says uh zimba y
in the Sanskrit is graa okay graa uh
guess what English word comes from
graa grab grabbing grab yeah so it means
holding okay and we had a we had a
holding called Dar dur also means to
hold okay uh Dharma comes from that the
word Dharma comes from that Dharma means
ring
definition of
Dharma that thing which holds its own
nature is Dharma okay that's the
definition of Dharma the word Dharma
comes from the word dur which means
holding tree comes from that truth comes
from that okay uh they are solid solid
steady things okay trees in the ancient
times were the steadiest thing around
okay uh so that's why they call them d
three three okay then they came to be
called threee okay so Dharma is
holding the Mantra that we use for
medicine bua the Mantra that we use to
ask for
help uh is called a dar it's technically
it's not called a mantra it's called a
Dar and dar means uh held or holding
okay and it and it means it has a
special nature
it holds a special nature which
is emptiness and then you have to think
about it and you have to understand that
a mantra won't work that mantras are
called holding
holders okay all right so he says here
uh you have to understand the Peace of
the doctor the patient and the medicine
or else there's no holding okay you
can't it won't work the Mantra won't
work all right
then next
one I think it's uh dominoes let see
yeah okay you got you can sell those
medicines
later okay if you sit in a if you sit in
a Buddhist talk and and cough everyone
going to give you medicine and then then
you can sell it
later
okay uh say l do
L uh suang no you want to describe L dog
loudly
reverse
backward reverse back
sorry I'm trying to L dog my
sneeze oh going
forward going forward sorry uh L Jung
means uh The Wheel of Life when it goes
one 2 3 4 5 6
7 sorry L dog means the other way around
yeah to and this is how you stop the
will Wheel of Life when Butchie gets
here who drew the Wheel of Life uh the
artist who did the first one is coming
today uh but uh normally that wheel goes
one two 3 four five up to 12 and then
that's called L Jun which means uh how
it starts the process of how it starts
you okay you trying to catch my
boogers I thought there was some more
money down there okay no it's okay it's
okay no it's not that it's not that it's
yeah
it's uh L Jung means uh if you don't
understand things that will trigger
fresh Karma and Etc 1 2 3 4 12 then lung
dog means uh turning the wheel around
okay turning the wheel around turning
the Wheel of Life around I always
thought it meant 12 11 10 9 8 it's not
true that's not what Lok is what is Lok
stop yeah stop One Stop two stop two
stop three stop three stop four okay
that's L okay if you stop the source of
the problem you stop the problem okay
and that's that's where we're going to
now okay thank you
okay uh let's do the next one
Francisco yeah I bow down to the
Conqueror the one gone does
oops
oops the defeater of the enemy the pure
and totally Enlighten Buddha with this
name of king of glory whose name is
proced to the corners of the Universe I
make offerings to you and I take my
shelter in you uh we are
starting the seven what preliminaries
again for the second time in the S okay
we had won General seven preliminaries
at the beginning
and that was to get to know this lineage
okay and again this is a special lineage
of medicine Buddha you are you are in a
second lineage now okay this is not the
general medicine Buddha lineage general
medicine Buddha lineage started 500 BC
this lineage started around I don't know
1500 okay uh with the great Fifth and
supposed to be medicine Buddha came to
the great fifth
and started this lineage and
so the beginning of of this sudden of
the beginning of this method of reaching
medicine
Buddha uh they teach you all the lineage
this new lineage it's called the second
lineage okay this is the second lineage
of medic Buddha so now you are in both
lineages I got both lineages in my life
okay from s who came to our Temple do
you remember the the llama with the
beard long time ago how many years ago
50 years ago okay and
um he was a great Tanta and he gave us
medicine Buddha practice uh also the
damous teacher
came and gave it gave us that initiation
so uh so anyway uh this is a prayers we
finished the seven preliminaries with
the the lineage okay and now we're doing
the seven preliminaries over again to
the eight medicine Buddhas okay to the
eight the gang of eight guys in the
medicine
Buddha people ask me which Diamond W
practice do you do which one do you
enjoy I'm vaj yini forget it I'm totally
in love with
Vini which is a female Buddha
and it for me it's a lot more I feel a
lot more connection to a female Buddha
uh but
um this is all guys okay this is like a
soccer team or
something I mean a male
soccer so uh I don't know if it's more
attractive to you that's fine okay uh
and and I'm looking forward to teaching
uh more about
yini uh but
uh in the everybody has their
own you know taste some people like
cinnamon rolls some people like
yot you know and Diamond way is a very
personal thing maybe you're attracted to
the eight guys maybe you're attracted to
vagini maybe you're attracted to Tara
you know it's it's very much a personal
choice okay Diamond way should be a
personal choice so my job is to give you
uh a selection of candy your job is to
choose which one you want to eat okay
question I hope it's good I only
interrupted my teacher once in my
life since they're enlightened beings
couldn't
they since they're enlightened beings
could they not appear in the female form
as well they could appear anywh they
want yeah what never will help people
yeah yeah they have that
power but they do it but our
seeds dra elicit our seeds draw out male
or female from them and then and then we
get to know them as a male or a female
so it's our seeds that make medicine
Buddha look like a boy soccer team and
it's our seeds that make bagini look
like bagini so and that's okay hey
that's
valid is
it is it interchangeable yes is it
really one or the other
yes
okay all right good okay uh so what's
happening in in the sadna now when you
reach this part uh we're starting a
second round of the seven prelimin
preliminaries we're starting through the
seventh preliminaries again and the
fifth Dil he mixes the first two okay he
puts them together I I make offering to
you and I take my shelter in you okay so
he's mixing the the first two I bow down
to you and I make offering to you
shelter here means I bow down to you
okay so these are the first two of the
preliminaries and they're always
together for the eight Buddhists okay
all right and this is the first of the
Buddhists the Buddhists have long names
the medicine Buddhist and they have
short names okay like this is the
passport name and then there's the short
name okay what's the short name here's
the long name you tell me the short name
for zero
dollars uh king of glory whose name is
proclaimed to the corners of the
universe good name he's just called Mr
good name okay so I like the short name
person I like the short name you know I
don't like the passport
name I like the friendly name okay so
anyway we're starting good name and
uh I felt kind of guilty because I
didn't get your good name really I spent
the whole course on good
name uh good name made Aid
prayers this Buddha made eight famous
prayers and uh I would like like to
explore with you the emptiness of his
eight prayers which means we're never
going to get to the second
bir okay and I'm sorry for that uh but
we just have a lot of things to do
okay I I'm of the I kind of feel like uh
we should just take our time and enjoy
the trip and I'm not in a rush to get to
the East Coast or the way you know let's
just enjoy trip and when we get there we
get there okay if we have to pick up
next life it's
okay right that's okay yeah we'll meet
again you know okay all right uh so
let's get to the
next uh here's the Real L I think
it's h wait a minute
really h do you have a number
40 uh
5.40 there you
go can you show the English yeah there
you go okay when you stop the mistake
misunderstanding stops when you stop
misunderstanding fresh camera and the
rest come to stop as well okay uh and
this refers to the Wheel of Life okay
this refers to the Wheel of Life why why
you
are sick in the first place why you need
medicine budha is the first link of The
Wheel of Life which
is uh yeah there's something you didn't
understand and by the way if we can wake
up
Butchie we're g to talk about that book
uh these guys were there when we
translated it the first time 50 years
ago or
something okay uh but uh when you stop
the
mistake uh misunderstanding stop okay
so for example with medicine Buddha what
would be the
mistake yeah thinking medicine Buddha
comes from medicine Buddha son okay it's
like the pen right it's like the dog
with the pen right if you think medicine
Buddha comes from medicine Buddha you
made a mistake that's that's the classic
mistake
tomorrow we have our weekly translation
class uh Saturday translation class and
we're gonna have word Smith here uh he's
gonna
come uh and I'm not making any beds
Tomorrow there's the one guy always wins
all the money uh
yeah he'll come here tomorrow and we'll
be going very deep about this mistake
okay his book is going to go very deep
about the mistake that we make and it's
the Mother book of the Mind only school
it was written by
Toma okay and it's an extraordinary book
about uh the mind only school okay and
we're gonna talk about the mistake
tomorrow okay it's a big big subject
okay we are making some mistake we go to
the temple we see medicine Buddhist
statue we pray to the medicine Buddhist
statue and the last thing you're
thinking is that they are coming from
you okay in in Christian religion I grew
up Christian you kind of think you come
from them you see what I
mean uh you know they made
you you know but in Buddhism kind of you
make
them okay like that you created them and
if you don't think that if you don't
understand that they don't work it
doesn't work okay if you don't
understand where they're coming from
they cannot be your doctor okay it won't
be successful okay but gu I mean a
doctor who comes from me is going to be
a pretty terrible
doctor you know I'm I I'm I'm not a
great person you know like I have all my
mistakes I have all my my bad habits I'm
not I'm not I'm an okay person I mean I
didn't blow up any cities or anything
but I'm not you know some Buddha you
know I'm just a normal person how can I
create a Buddha how can you say the
medicine of Buddha came from me and
really it is
impossible but you did
it okay and there's many many parts of
the universe where there's no medicine
bu because the people there haven't got
the seeds
to create a medicine Buddha okay so if
you're in a world that has not one
medicine Buddha but
eight uh it means you're a special
person okay it really does mean that
you're a special person so you know one
of the most difficult things as a
teacher which you guys will find out you
know is that people refuse to admit that
they are good you know people fight it
you know you say you're good and they
say no I'm bad they say no you're good
they say no I'm bad then they say if you
think you're bad then confess I don't
want
to okay anyway uh you created the
medicine bua you created all eight of
them okay and if you don't think so you
can't they can't help you if you don't
understand where they're coming from
they can't help you that's why we're
having Nar in a class with medicine
Buddha class I can teach you the prayers
we can do the mantras together and go
home and pray you know we hope that your
cancer goes away or something like that
I mean that's what 99% of people
do but it doesn't work and and here's
the gari of says it doesn't work okay
and by the way Nar uh Stanley was with
me Stanley and Alison we were in Lima
Peru
we were in a little coffee shop we were
there for five hours if I'm not
mistaken and U I was working
on uh neoga's books like what did ngoga
write and most people know about his
umaro six books he wrote six famous
books and we did a study Stanley Al over
there we did a study on John Brady's
database we found 141 one books by by
thearer okay and they are amazing okay
John Brady has most people if you ask
them how what did the G write they will
say six books and then uh we use John
Brady's data
base which cost about $15 million so far
and it's now the 35th anniversary of the
database and it's free it's totally free
okay and if you use it if you know how
to use it you we found 141 books by n
Gard so there's something for you guys
to
translate I'm leaving a few for
you okay all right uh if you stop Miss
understanding the medicine Buddhas you
will stop fresh Karma okay if you stop
link number one you stop link number two
for
$50
what's the two pictures for link number
one and Link number
two and since since the gang translated
the book he doesn't get the answer Mar
Marana
Mariana all
right this is a blind
person for link number one
misunderstanding misunderstanding and
Link number two
uh is creating karma is a person who is
making pots good okay good 50
bucks uh and again there's L dog here
okay if you stop link number one that's
stops number link number two if you stop
link number two you stop link number
three there's a Jackie Chen
movie good
one the the people who made it were
really smart cuz they got the best
Chinese actor and the best Indian actor
and the best American actor so they can
sell the movie in three
markets H so the the I think the lady is
from India and Jackie Chen is Jackie
Chen and there's some Americans in there
and
anyway there's a conveyor
belt and the lady is stuck on it and
there's this knife that's going like
this you know and then Jackie Chen's
running around Jackie Chen's fighting
with some guy who's trying to stop him
from pulling the lady off the conveyor B
and then finally he jams uh some kind of
metal stick into the Machinery okay and
I'll give a $100 for that you
ready
uh
got very
quiet
uh when you looking for
the special place on the machine where
you can stop it okay if you if you push
a a piece of metal there this whole
machine will die you know it's the weak
point of the
machine uh give me the
Sanskrit
she decides
[Applause]
no huh
marah yeah marah say
marah Okay
marma comes from it's
Sanskrit and the root is myr which means
to Die the root is myr which means to
die AMTA comes from that AMTA means
don't die Mortuary
murder they all come from M okay hat
comes from an ancient rot Han which
means to strike what's the English word
that came from
that gun gun comes from Han comes from
Hut okay marah means shoot the shoot the
crucial Point killing Point yeah shoot
shoot the killing Point okay what's the
killing point in The Wheel of Life
yeah link number one that's the only
place you can stop the machine okay if
you don't
know where the weak point in the machine
is and you keep fighting the machine
your whole life it you won't succeed it
won't stop okay you got to know the
killing Point mahata okay you got and
there's a there's two examples in
Tantra
what are they do you
remember there's two examples
of I I'll just tell you one is uh when
you want to kill a
tree when I came to Rashi gine they her
St germa's husband hungar just finished
the temple with dorsa and the other
guys and uh they were uh I don't know
there's this big
uh all the construction stuff was I got
there like the day after they finished
which was good
luck uh but there was construction piles
of construction garbage and there was a
big tree a big oak tree you know and my
teacher you I don't know if you know the
story Ken remember told me get rid of
the oak trees it was a stump they cut
the tree but the stump was there and he
was always trying to find words work for
me because I I I was a young man trying
to be celebrate and
uh so he's like dig that tree out you
know and I'm like okay it took me about
three
years uh to dig the tree out you know
and in Tantra there's a famous uh
example uh of
mahata there's a tap rot you know tap
rot
Tap Root means the it's the main channel
that the water is carried from the roots
to the to the branches there's a main
channel uh tap rot in a lot of trees the
tap rot is in the bark it's not in the
middle of the tree in a lot of trees the
bark carries the water up to the limbs
and the leaves not the there's not some
center of the tree or something Angelo
can tell you because he's a tree expert
for a cityan in Canada he he planted all
the trees for the whole city
yay if you want to know the name of the
city you have to catch a
Cole
go it's it's go
go I went there they asked me to teach
there there's like 12 people in the town
and um no there's how many I don't know
50,000
150,000 any yeah anyway uh so that's uh
when you find the tap rot in a tree and
you take a a piece of wood of a spike
and you tap it into the you block the
water the water channel the tree will
fall down on itself own it takes a
while but the tree I had a tree like
that I really wanted to have a carab
tree in my
house because this is where I met my
wife was under a carab
tree a it's called carab it's a special
tree you want to know the whole
story carab uh carab grows in the
Mediterranean it's a tree it has a long
bean and inside the bean there are
special
seeds and no what no matter where that
tree grows in the world the seeds weigh
the
same so the seeds are no matter where
the tree grows whether it gets water it
doesn't get water fertilizer no
fertilizer the seeds are the same weight
exactly so in ancient times when they
had to weigh something tiny they
developed carrots from the carab tree
carrot is the seed of the carab tree so
like a a 14 karat diamond 14 karat gold
18 karat gold uh one karat diamond these
are all carrots okay anyway I met my
wife under a carab tree so I wanted to
have a carab tree in my backyard but the
truck can't go there because the toilet
stuff's under the
ground so I hired a
crane and they lifted it over the house
and they put it in the backyard it was
kind of
expensive uh but they put the strap
around the bar and they they they cut
off one tiny circle of bar and it killed
the
tree yeah because there was no water
that was marah okay got it that's that's
the first example of Mah second example
is chor which means um yantra in
Sanskrit which is an ancient word for a
secret mandala or something
yantra uh it's similar to Mand ra okay
and this is a killing machine that was
used to guard the king's
gold and uh it was a huge wheel with
ropes machine in ancient times thousands
of years ago and then it it they had
statues of soldiers with swords and if
you go in there it detects you coming in
and then the machine start starts to
move and it it it cuts your head
off but there's a weak point in the
machine if you like crawl in and you you
put a stick in it the whole machine
breaks got it that's killing Point
that's Mar Mah okay uh so here they
say uh when you go at the Wheel of Life
when
you when you ask medicine Buddha for
help it's not going to work if you don't
know the killing Point okay you you
won't be able to stop cancer heart
attack things like that
diabetes if you don't know the killing
Point okay and the killing point is
knowing where it comes from the killing
point is knowing that the cancer comes
from you
okay and that's the only way medicine
Buddha can help you medicine Buddha
cannot help you if you don't understand
the killing Point yourself okay there's
a famous ID
20 bucks
Stanley do you know those guys offered
me 20 bucks for every American idiom I
teach
them and they never paid
me just kidding next
M uh then I forgot the
IDI yeah any I'll tell
you anyway you have to know where to
kill it you have to know where to hit
where to strike okay you have to know
where to strike killing Point okay
medicine Buddha doesn't work if you
don't know where to strike okay your
disease okay if you don't know where to
strike your disease medicine Buddha
doesn't work okay what's the place to
strike your
disease understand where it's coming
from okay understand where it's coming
from in the
end every disease you ever have is
coming for you that's kind of why I'm so
impatient with doctors you know people
you know people always offering to send
me to a doctor or something I'm like you
know it's okay I understand where it's
coming from you know and and I'll take
I'll try to take care of it myself I I'm
not saying don't go to a doctor but take
care of the karma first then go to the
doctor and that's medicine B of practice
and that's what nag is saying here okay
and if you don't understand nag you
cannot practice medicine Buddha okay you
can do the mantras nothing's going to
happen okay and that's what happened for
most of the last 2,000
years all right and we got a few minutes
we're gonna take questions in in three
minutes am I right
Tim yes
okay and I want to finish one more thing
Let me
see
[Music]
yeah I think you guys is
5.41 that's the lady who's sick I
think
right uh we are starting chapter 24 of
the book called wisdom we are starting
chapter
24 of the book called wisdom the book
has 27 chapters
total okay we when we started
this Retreat we had six chapters left to
do and now we're on the third one okay
we're starting we did 22 23 and now
we're going to start 24 we will never
finish
24 uh I mean hopefully by Sunday we can
finish chapter 24 okay we're going to
work on it okay then next year we have
to do 25 26 and 27 okay all right and
then we'll be done all right
so the first prayer the the first prayer
of good name is
what and I'm not I mean I don't if you
ask me I wouldn't know either uh it
happens to be for sick people
okay and oh hang
on
huh
oh wow that is the
tree uh it's in a
garden if you ever saw that book
okay who took that W nice
job yeah it's in a church
Garden
okay can you go back to 5.39 you
guys it's a
quotation uh one more I think go back
one more
there
5.39 uh it should say recite these
lines come on I put numbers on there
5.39 it says recite these
lines okay
anyway uh it's true
traditional uh when you ask the medicine
Buddhist for help you have to repeat it
seven times okay and and we'll be seeing
that with each of the seven medicine
Buddhist okay technically there's seven
medicine
Buddhists and then there's a tour
manager called
shakuni and he brings them to us okay
so
uh
why you have to recite it seven times
because in the sna you're going to have
to recite these lines not the whole s
but each time you bow down and each time
you ask for help you're supposed to
repeat it seven
times well there's seven medicine
Buddhists that makes sense I'll tell you
my
opinion you won't remember that he's
coming from you for seven
times okay like if you just say I bow
down to you I take refuge in you and you
keep going you won't remember that it's
coming from your seats I think in my
opinion the reason you repeat it seven
times is it gives you time to remember
they're coming from your seats okay it
gives you time to remember they're
coming from your SE okay so when you
recite it seven times don't waste your
time okay don't pay attention to the
first one and and then just space out on
the other six same with your mantras
okay same when you do your mantras in
Retreat
okay uh the reason you do a million
mantras in a l
room is uh and we did we did a thousand
days right we did threeyear
Retreat uh each time you do the Mantra
you have to think about why why they're
coming from you okay if you don't think
about that and you just do the mantra
it's a waste of time okay you're just
wasting your time okay
cool all right um questions and I'm
going to let who's picking the an the
questioner okay I'll leave it up to you
guys talk loud and talk slow how many
languages we got
Tim 12 we are translating into 12
languages Okay so those poor translaters
they by the end of the week they're
like so talk slow and take your
time first question Gesa it comes from
online um it's a it's a why
question so why should I bow down and
ask for help from the medicine Buddha if
my true Pro protection is the 10
virtuous Deeds
yeah good good question
um this is the weird thing okay uh if
they're coming from me why do I have to
talk to them
anyway you know uh if they're coming
from me why do I have to talk to them
anyway and the garer would say if
they're not coming from you why would
you have to talk to them
anyway Theo will answer the question
with a question
okay if they're coming from me why I
have to ask them for help and the g says
well if they're not coming from you then
why do you have to ask them for help you
know okay and that's nar's famous answer
to that first question okay if if a
person's coming from me then why do I
even have to talk to them and then
theist theist answers always the same
how could you talk to them if they
weren't coming from you answer me that
and then I'll answer your question okay
and we never get to the answer right
because they are coming from you
okay
get get over it my teacher said get over
it get over it they're coming from me
right yes and I still have to ask them
for help yes get over it you know okay
yes they're coming from you and you
still have to ask them for help and you
still have to bow down to them why I
have to bow down to someone who's coming
from me you still have to do it okay and
the only way you can bow down is if you
understand where they're coming from
otherwise you're bowing down to the
wrong person got it okay all
right next question so another question
from online this is from Galina and
she's a a big ACI volunteer and Y she's
everywhere so thank you very much for
all your help
Galina so here's a this question is if a
doctor is constantly
healing why does he
consistently see sick
patients oh yeah because the patients
don't listen to the
[Laughter]
doctor okay that's pretty
easy so the doctor has the karma for the
patients not to listen to them that's
true yeah so if the doctor changed that
Karma then they would stop saying sick
patients yeah
okay
Al yeah yeah that's why why there's a
I'll tell you a famous thing okay uh did
the AR the Buddhist by the way this is
the opening lines of the pran vartia
right it it we
had which is beginning formal logic
study but there's a
[Music]
preface most normal people are attracted
to normal
stuff and they don't have any
wisdom they don't have any quick
wisdom therefore they have absolutely no
interest in my
book saying not only
that uh they also very jealous when I
write a book okay okay
[Music]
Chini because of this
situation
uh therefore I'm not claiming that my
book's going to help
anybody and he said I'm just writing
this book to review it for
myself okay that's the opening lines of
of one of the five greatest books in
history it's like I know you guys don't
care I don't care I'm still gonna write
the book to help myself okay what was
the
question no it means look the doctor
knows the patient's not going to listen
but the doctor wants to get the method
of the Cure deeper into the doctor's
mind so the doctor can be cured okay so
that's a common Buddhist question okay
like why should I teach if the students
don't listen you gu La you're teaching
for yourself you're teaching to improve
yourself you should be the first patient
the first patient should be the doctor
right okay okay next question
too by the way that's Dharma I love
those lines I I love
them um how about Tracy
yay I work with a lot of people who've
had trauma a lot of traumas and um a lot
of PTSD and a lot of children who
haven't had resources that they needed
so my my question is I know it's my
mirror but when I see the
self-compassion and self- love ignite
within them a lot of magic happens but I
also feel a lot of obstacles getting
through it so what can you share in
regards to self-compassion and self-love
that could be possibly beneficial to
anybody that relates to this yeah good
okay
uh
so here's a little I I told you this
story but I'll tell you um so I was uh
asked to go to a house in
California uh the mother asked me to go
meet the child and um the child is
severely
autistic and she said is there anything
you can do for the child you know and
I'm
like uh helping someone improve their
seeds that process requires that the
person you're helping make some effort
to improve their seeds so how do you
convey to a seriously autistic
child uh how do you get them to improve
their seats you know and and we actually
worked on it for a year me and the mom
you know I went back home I would write
her we would talk about it and we came
up with this thing
um uh she would take the autistic child
to the hospital she would buy presents
for the other children children's
hospital she would buy presents for the
other children in the hospital then she
would put her son next to the the sick
kids and she'd put a gift in her son's
hands a toy and then she would hold his
hands and then we would move his hands
to the other kid and then we'd pull his
hands off and the gift would drop out in
the other kid's lap and he'd be
like you know so we did this for a year
and qu we figured the karma has four
steps right
she and there's no intention he has no
intention he's
not it's not his will to give a gift to
the other child but there's a tarton
which in ABI Dharma means there is a
completion of the action okay he did
complete the action he didn't intend to
complete the action but he completed the
action it's like when you drive your car
and you kill
insects uh there's no motivation you
don't say I'm going to go out and kill
some insects you just drive to the store
and you kill some insects but there is
completion uh there's no intention to
kill the insects but you do kill them so
there's not heavy Karma because the main
Karma comes from your intention but
there is the karma of completion we call
it the karma of completion okay so that
kid had the karma of completion but no
Karma of intention which is much much
less but it works it's a little bit okay
it's a little bit so we did this for a
year and then I came back she said she I
was in teaching California and and she
she said come to the house I want I want
to show you something and I went back to
the house and um I sat she said sit down
and the boy came in and he sat down at
the piano and he played like a Beethoven
Sonata wow perfect you know cuz artistic
kids have this attention they have a
limited but very powerful
attention and and then he now he plays
music and he's a he's a good musician
and uh so I think uh when you have a
problem like
that uh you kind of uh put the children
into situations where they have to
rejoice in their goodness and keep
putting in in that situation
artificially and then uh it will change
their seeds you see what I mean uh so
keep putting them artificially into
situations where they have to admit that
they did something right and then uh and
then those seeds will take
over and even when there's not much
intention okay